till now we have looked at the five key architectural decisions that we need to think about to make
production grade application. Now in the next few lectures we are going to look at the
sixth architectural decision which is how to optimize your JNA application cost.
Now let's go ahead and look at some of the cost optimization strategies.
Now first let's look at bedrock pricing models. So there are three pricing models is bedrock.
We have on-demand provision throughput and batch. Now let's go ahead and understand each of them
in more detail. So first we have the on-demand mode and in on-demand mode you just pay for what you use.
So there are no time base term commitments. So I don't have to commit for one month,
three months or six months to use that model. So you just pay based on what you use.
So let's say if we just make 10 requests or a period of three months then you just pay for
those 10 requests. Now how are they charged for text generation models? So they are charged
based on every input token processed and every output token generated. So usually when you
make a request if it is up to 1000 tokens so you'll be charged x amount of dollars and that would
vary based on model to model and we'll get into those details. But just remember 1000 tokens are
approximate equal to 750 words. So if you're making a request and they are less than 750 words
then that will be equal to one EPA request. Then for image generation model so if you're
generating image you will be charged on every image generated and then similarly for emitting models
you are charged again for every input token processed. Okay so that's on-demand mode.
So next we have provision throughput. They are primarily designed for large consistent
inference workload that need guaranteed throughput. So if you have any critical generic application
which uses these models in production then you might be better off using the provision throughput
mode because it guarantees consistent throughput. So what is the pricing model for
provision throughput? You can purchase model units for specific base or custom model with time
commitment. So here you have to commit for one or six months and then you also decide specific
model units depending on number of requests, number of tokens and so on. So you have to select
number of model units and you have to select the time commitment. Okay then finally we have the
batch inferencing and batch inferencing allows you to run model inferences asynchronously
in batches to efficiently process many requests at once. Now let's take an example. Let's say you
work in a legal department and you have to summarize hundreds of large documents but you don't
need that immediately and they can run let's say on an overnight batch. So in that case what
you do is you upload all your documents in an S3 bucket and then just create a batch inference job
and highlight which bedrock large damage model you want to use and then what it's going to do is
it's going to generate an output in the target S3 bucket as a JSON file. So AWS says that batch
inferences can speed up inferences on large data sets and what's most important is that in some cases
batch inferences can be 50% lower price compared to the on-demand inference pricing. Okay so that's
pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see you in the next lecture. Thank you.